<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.5">
  <compounddef id="md__home_nbentley_Trophia_Code_www_src_projects_P00004_Alfonsino" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md__home_nbentley_Trophia_Code_www_src_projects_P00004_Alfonsino</compoundname>
    <title>P00004 Alfonsino</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Title: P00004: Characterisation of the Alfonsino fishery in BYX 3 Tags: Adam Langley, Nokome Bentley, Paul Starr, Nathan Walker</para><para>Trophia was contracted by the New Zealand Ministry of Fisheries (MFish) to characterise the alfonsino (Beryx splendens ) fishery by analysis of existing commercial catch and effort data and data from other sources; and make recommendations on appropriate methods to monitor or assess the status of this fishstock. The specific objectives for this project include:</para><para><orderedlist>
<listitem><para>To characterise the BYX fishery by analysis of existing commercial catch and effort data and data from other sources; and make recommendations on appropriate methods to monitor and assess the status of this fishstock.</para></listitem><listitem><para>To develop a standardised CPUE index for the BYX 3 fishery using data from the catch and effort database up to the end of the 1999/2000 fishing year.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Describe the interaction between the fisheries for alfonsino and bluenose in QMA 3.</para></listitem></orderedlist>
</para><para>This study was financed by MFish project BYX2000-01</para><para>Outputs that will soon be available from this site include:</para><para>Langley, A.D.; Walker, N. (2002). CPUE analysis of the target BYX 3 alfonsino fishery and associated bluenose bycatch. New Zealand Fisheries Assessment Report 2002/24. 45 p. Download file</para><para>Langley, A.D.; Walker, N. (2002). Characterisation of the alfonsino (Beryx splendens) fishery in BYX 3. New Zealand Fisheries Assessment Report 2002/29. 40 p. </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
