<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.5">
  <compounddef id="md__home_nbentley_Trophia_Code_www_src_projects_P09012_Vessels" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md__home_nbentley_Trophia_Code_www_src_projects_P09012_Vessels</compoundname>
    <title>P09012 Vessels</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Title: P09012: Characterizing the New Zealand commercial fishing fleet: patterns and changes</para><para>Principal Investigator: Nokome Bentley Researchers: Adam Langley Philippe Lallemande, (NZ Seafood Industry Council Ltd.) Paul Starr Status: Completed Trophia has been contracted by the New Zealand Ministry of Fisheries (MFish) to provide a characterization of the structure of, and changes to, commercial fishing activities in New Zealand since 1990. The specific objectives for this project include:</para><para><orderedlist>
<listitem><para>Define segments of commercial fishing activities based on catch composition, method and location.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Summarise trends in numbers and characteristics of vessels, methods used, and quota and ACE holdings and transactions for each fishery segment .</para></listitem></orderedlist>
</para><para>A broad characterization of commercial fishing activities in New Zealand is much needed. There is substantial institutional knowledge within the Ministry of Fisheries, research providers and the fishing industry itself, on the structure and changes in the commercial fleet since the introduction of the Quota Management System. However, what is lacking is a single, up to date, document that provides an overview of patterns and changes in the commercial fleet and the activities they undertake. Such a document, based on a formal analysis of the available data, would be useful as a general reference for fisheries managers, scientists and stakeholders. For example, it would be useful in developing Fishery Plans and in the interpretation of standardised catch-per-unit-effort (CPUE) analyses that are conducted annually for a variety of fisheries .</para><para>Our proposed methodology begins by dividing commercial fishing activities into discrete segments based upon catch composition, methods used and location. For each segment defined, we will then do detailed summaries of vessel numbers and characteristics, fishing methods used, and quota and ACE (Annual Catch Entitlement) holdings and transactions. These summaries will include examinations of how segment attributes have changed through time.</para><para>This work is funded by MFish project SEC2009/02 </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
