<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.5">
  <compounddef id="md__home_nbentley_Trophia_Code_www_src_projects_P08008_SNA8" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md__home_nbentley_Trophia_Code_www_src_projects_P08008_SNA8</compoundname>
    <title>P08008 SNA8</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Title: P08008: Relative abundance of snapper in SNA 8</para><para>Principal Investigator: Terese Kendrick Researchers: Nokome Bentley Status: Completed Trophia has been contracted by the New Zealand Ministry of Fisheries (MFish) to determine relative abundance for snapper in SNA 8.. The specific objective for this project include:</para><para><orderedlist>
<listitem><para>To characterise the SNA 8 fishery and update the CPUE analyses for trawl fisheries in each area of SNA 8 using data up to the end of 2007-08 .</para></listitem></orderedlist>
</para><para>The snapper fishery is New Zealand’s most valuable inshore finfish fishery by value. SNA 8 is the second largest commercial snapper fishery. Snapper also support important fisheries for recreational fishers and Maori.</para><para>The 2005 stock assessment indicated that current biomass (start of year 2004–05) was between 8% and 12% B0 and the biomass was predicted to slowly increase at the TACC level of 1500 t. However, from 1 October 2005 the TACC was reduced to 1300 t to ensure a faster rebuild of the stock.</para><para>The stock assessments for snapper rely mainly on the absolute abundance estimates from tagging programmes. Absolute abundance of SNA 8 was last estimated in 2002 and the next mark-recapture study is scheduled for 2011. Standardized CPUE series, updated every three years, are used to provide crude indices of relative abundance in the periods between tagging programmes. The SNA 8 CPUE index was last updated to the end of the 2003/04 fishing year (SNA 2004-01).</para><para>According to the Snapper Medium Term Research Plan, it is assumed that the stock will be monitored using standardized CPUE (updated every three years) and annual catch-at- age until the 2012 assessment.</para><para>This work is funded by MFish project SNA2008/01 </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
