<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.5">
  <compounddef id="md__home_nbentley_Trophia_Code_www_src_projects_P09003_MSE" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md__home_nbentley_Trophia_Code_www_src_projects_P09003_MSE</compoundname>
    <title>P09003 MSE</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Title: P09003: Management strategy evaluation for data-poor fishstocks</para><para>Principal Investigator: Mark Maunder Researchers: Nokome Bentley Status: Completed Trophia has been contracted by Quantitative Resource Assessment LLC (Mark Maunder) in coordination with the California Ocean Protection Council (OPC) and the California Department of Fish and Game (CDFG) to develop an MSE approach for data-poor stocks. The specific objectives for this project include:</para><para><orderedlist>
<listitem><para>MSE for generic fisheries: Describe the evaluation of management strategies for generic (archtypal) fisheries..</para></listitem><listitem><para>Tailored MSE: Evaluate one or more. of Calefornia&apos;s data-poor stocks.</para></listitem></orderedlist>
</para><para>The generic MSE will include archetypes that can be applied to such data-poor Calefornia fisheries as teh nearshore finfish fishery and the Calefornia lobster fishery. Also to provide information on how to apply these MSE (i.e. MDE decision tree). In addition, identify and prioritize the type of data that are critical to such evaluations.</para><para>The tailored MSE will evaluate one or more of Calefornia&apos;s data-poor stocks using MSE tailored to (uses the biological parameters and data available from) these stocks.</para><para>Outputs from this project will include three client reports.</para><para>This work is funded by Quantitative Resource Assessment LLC (Mark Maunder) in coordination with the California Ocean Protection Council (OPC) and the California Department of Fish and Game (CDFG) </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
